Bùi Thành Nhân

I'm a senior software engineer specialized in **web development** with a strong focus on the backend and **DevOps**.

I have 10 years of experience working in a variety of environments: outsource and product startups, remote and onsite, with international teams across multiple timezones.

I also develop various types of open source software as a hobby, not only to solve immediate problems and satisfy my intellectual curiosity, but also to evaluate interesting emerging technologies.

Year of birth: 1993 Gender: Male

Location: HCMC, Vietnam Blog: https://hi.imnhan.com Email: hi@imnhan.com

FOSS: https://github.com/nhanb
Web version: https://cv.imnhan.com
PDF version: BuiThanhNhan.pdf

- Professional experience: Git, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Django, Django REST Framework, Docker, Docker Compose, ReactJS, AWS, GCP, Microsoft Azure, Ansible, Kafka, Redis, REST APIs, GitHub, GitLab, GitLab CI, Datadog, Sentry, AWS Lambda.
- Casual experience (through hobby projects): Go, Tcl/Tk, Zig, Tkinter, SQLite, Flask, GitHub Actions, SourceHut, Nginx, Caddy, systemd, Makefiles, pyinfra, Tailscale, cross-platform desktop GUI programming, socket programming, static site generators, shell scripting, amateur woodworking.

EXPERIENCE

MODEC

Senior Software Engineer - Backend & Infrastructure (10/2023 – Current)

- Developed backend for an internal web-based human resources management system for FPSO vessel construction projects.
- Maintained infrastructure-as-code repo that utilized terraform to manage Azure cloud resources.
- Wrote internal developer tooling to aid in selective feature rollouts.
- Collaborated with Product Owners to develop features, which involved architectural decisions and effort estimation.
- Technologies: Python, Django REST Framework, Postgres, Docker, Microsoft Azure Cloud.

Inspectorio

Senior Software Engineer - Backend (02/2021 – 01/2023)

- Developed backend for a B2B SaaS product that streamlines the physical goods inspection workflow.
- Introduced in-memory caching layer for authentication service responses that improved average end-to-end API response time by $\sim 30\%$.
- Performed rigorous code review.
- Performed feature estimation for cycle and sprint planning.
- Mentored more junior engineers via code review, pair programming and coaching on topics like Git workflows.
- Wrote internal getting-started guide for onboarding Backend Engineers.
- Technologies: Python, Django REST Framework, Postgres, Docker, Google Cloud Platform.

Parcel Perform

Senior Software Engineer - Backend (02/2018 – 03/2020)

- · Worked on backend for:
 - parcelperform.com & parcelmonitor.com: a set of microservices that make up a suite of parcel tracking utilities for businesses. Relies heavily on kafka message queues and docker containers.
 - <u>lockeralliance.net</u>: Singapore's federated smart locker system which provides a single consistent interface for locker operators and logistics service providers to interoperate.
- Technologies: Python, Django REST Framework, Postgres, Docker Compose, AWS.

East Agile

Senior Software Developer - Fullstack (06/2016 – 01/2018)

- Maintained backend and single-page-app frontend for the Citizen Police Data Project (<u>cpdp.co</u>), a highly interactive visualization of an extensive Chicago police misconduct database.
- Performed pair programming and applied rigorous Test-Driven Development.
- Technologies: Python, JavaScript, React/Redux, Django REST Framework, Ansible.

Cogini

Web Developer - Backend & Infrastructure (02/2014 – 04/2015)

- Developed web apps and implemented server-side API for mobile apps.
- · Maintained configuration management using Chef.
- · Technologies: Python, JavaScript, Postgres, nginx, Chef

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Pytaku

- A self-hosted web-based manga reader.
- Utilized a simple web stack with automated TLS cert management via Caddy.
- (Ab)used Google App Engine as an auto-IP-rotating proxy server for the web scraper.
- Experimented with bare minimum frontend dependencies (MithrilJS being the only non-cosmetic 3rd-party library), and simple bundling with esbuild.
- Technologies: Python, JavaScript, Flask, MithrilJS, SQLite, Caddy, Google App Engine, esbuild.

McRoss

- A minimalistic, cross-platform desktop GUI browser for the Gemini protocol.
- Technologies: Python, Tkinter, socket programming.

s4g

- Flexible static site generator that powers my own blog.
- Technologies: Go, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

GORTS

- Scoreboard overlay controller for fighting game streams. An earlier version of it was successfully used for <u>Saigon Cup</u> streams for multiple years that peaked at 22k concurrent viewers including restreams in Japanese & Mandarin.
- Technologies: Go, Tcl/Tk (previously Python, Tkinter), JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

boast

- Static git repo listing generator in the same spirit as Stagit but supports cloning without any further server side config.
- Experimented with Zig and an HTML builder instead of templates.
- Technologies: Zig, Git internals, HTML.

QUALIFICATIONS

RMIT International University Vietnam

Bachelor of Information Technology (2011–2014)

- GPA: **3.2/4**
- Full scholarship
- IT Club Vice President

IELTS Academic

Overall score: **8.5/9** (2012)

- Listening: 9Reading: 9Speaking: 7.5
- Writing: 7.5
- Featured on British Council's website (archive)

MISCELLANEOUS

- Source: https://github.com/nhanb/cv.imnhan.com/
- References available upon request